JONNAILA MARIE UMALIN

Bulacan, Philippines 09060751351 | umalin.jonnailamarie.1213@gmail.com | LinkedIn

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Conscientious and adaptive professional with a background in customer service, back-office support, team management, project management, data analysis, and research. Quality-oriented and efficient in performing time-sensitive tasks, with strong attention to detail. Passionate about data, continuous learning, and self-improvement.

WORK EXPERIENCE

ADMISSIONS ASSOCIATE

Pagoda Projects | November 2022 - Present

- Processed applications which include conducting interviews and evaluating CVs
- Managed multiple programs with different deadlines, processes, and targets.
- Maintained email templates and documents relevant to the programs
- Responded to inquiries or concerns via email, text, and phone
- Handled leads processing which entails reaching out via email, SMS, and calls
- Spearheaded other internal projects and managed ad-hoc tasks
- Collaborated and coordinated with other departments to ensure a smooth customer experience

• TEAM LEADER

TaskUs | June 2021 – June 2022

- Managed a team of 11 members
- Direct client communication.
- Spearheaded business reviews encompassing data extraction, analysis, and presentation.
- Liaise between internal and international teams for order processing. This
 includes weekly meetings with both teams.
- Spearheaded onboarding and training of new hires created onboarding timeline, presentation, and assessment, and handled the actual training itself
- Monitored the team's accuracy scores conducted weekly audits, and developed weekly newsletters which included process updates and knowledge checks.
- Conducted weekly 1-1 sessions with the purpose of coaching each team member and the goal of improving individual and team performance.

• BACK-OFFICE TEAM MEMBER

TaskUs | September 2020 - June 2021

- Part of the order fulfillment team. Handled order activation of a cloud-based project management tool.
- Reviewed purchase orders, quotes, and order forms.
- Counterchecked details and check for discrepancies or inaccuracies between customer documents and Salesforce entries.
- Successfully reached the daily quota of 75 processed orders per day

• CUSTOMER SERVICE REPRESENTATIVE

TaskUs | October 2018 – September 2020

 Assisted with product-related general inquiries, troubleshooting, and processing requests from customers.

- Monitored team quality scores and provided quality-related updates; extracted handling time (AHT) reports and sent out daily emails related to this KPI.
- Processed refunds, and escalations. Addressed order-related problems via email.

SKILLS

TECHNICAL

Knowledgeable with the following tools and applications:

Google Suite
Smartsheet
Salesforce
NetSuite
Microsoft Office
Podio
Zoom
Skype
HubSpot
Guru
WordPress
SQL

o Canva

SOFT SKILLS

Project Management
 Leadership
 Cultural Fluency and Intercultural
 Communication
 Strong Written and Verbal
 Communication
 Analytical
 Data Analysis
 Critical Thinking
 Problem-Solving
 Research
 Detail-oriented
 Teamwork
 Adaptability

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Arts in Communication Research – Cum Laude Polytechnic University of the Philippines Sta. Mesa, Manila

REFERENCES

Available upon request